根据之前的测试  我们成功地创建了数据库
We tested that the database was created successfully.
但是现在我们要测试一下是否能
But now we should test that reading from and
正确地从数据库中读写数据
writing to the sunshine database works as expected.
我会教大家如何向数据库中插入一行数据
I'll show you how we insert a row of data into the database, and
然后再从数据库中读出这行数据
then query the database to read it back out.
首先  我们需要通过SQLiteOpenHelper类拿到数据库的引用
First, we get a reference to the database from our SQLI Open Helper.
也就是一个SQLiteDatabase的实例
Which is an instance of an SQLI database object.
我们在测试创建数据库的时候用到了这个实例
We use this in test create DB.
由于我们需要向数据库写入数据
Since we're writing to the database,
并且从中读取数据  我们需要一个可写的数据库实例
as well as reading, we're going to get a writable database.
如果我们只需要读取数据  那么只需要一个可读的数据库实例就可以了
If we were only reading, then we should use a readable database.
我们使用ContentValues对象表示需要插入到
To represent the row of data, we want to insert into the database,
数据库中的一行数据
we use a content values object.
我们在createNorthPoleLocationValues
We create one of these,
工具方法中创建一个ContentValues对象
in the create North pole location values utility function.
ContentValues对象包含了一组键值对
Content values, contain a set of key value pairs.
你需要将字符串类型的键以及与其相关联的值存入ContentValues中
You put a key string associated with the value, into the content value set.
字符串类型的键是数据库中的属性名称
The key string is contain the names of columns in your database.
值则可以是多种数据类型
The value can contain many different data types.
ContentValues对象在Android里用于向数据库中写入数据
Content values, are used to write databases in Android.
一旦我们创建了ContentValues对象
Once we've created our content values.
就可以调用数据库实例的insert方法
We call database.insert,
将表名和ContentValues对象作为参数传入以创建一行新数据
with the table name and content values to actually create the new row of data.
插入操作的返回值是一个长整形
The return value, from our insertion is a long,
它是插入的新数据行的id属性
that contains the new row ID from the _ID column.
如果插入操作失败  返回值是-1
If there's an error inserting, the return value is negative 1.
现在我们有了这个id值  我们可以通过它从数据库中查询这一行数据
Now that we have a row ID, we can query the database for that row.
这里是各种有不同个数参数的重载的query方法
There are several query methods that take in different numbers of parameters.
查询方法只是帮助我们更加简单地
A query method, is just a helper function to make it
创建和执行一个SELECT语句
easier to construct and execute a select statement.
让我们来看看query方法是如何构建一个查询语句的
Let's show how the query function constructs a statement.
这里是一个SQLiteDatabase的基本的查询方法
Here's what the base, SQLiteDatabase query function looks like.
最基本的查询只需要一个表名作为参数
The most basic query we can make with this only has a table name.
这样会返回所有记录的所有属性
And it returns all columns and all records.
剩下的这些参数
The rest of the parameters,
可以对上面这个基本的输出结果进行过滤
would modifying filter the output of this query.
添加一个我们希望返回的属性列表的映射数组
Adding a projection, in array of columns, we wish to return,
会改变下面的SELECT语句所查询的内容
changes what we are selecting in select statement below.
selection参数会过滤查询结果
The selection parameter filters the results.
你也可以选择性地使用selection arguments参数来替换selection参数
One can optionally also use the selection arguments to replace any
中对应的问号占位符
question marks in the query.
Android将此作为绑定参数
Android creates these as bound parameters,
它是面向SQLite数据库的低层次接口  也就是说  我们不需要担心
in a low level interface to SQLite, which means, we don't have to worry
诸如转义字符串以保证查询的正确性这样的事情
about things like escaping the strings to keep the query valid.
我们在构建了上面这样的查询以后
We can also change the selection arguments,
依然可以改变selection参数
after our query has been made this way.
最后一个参数  你应该可以猜到  会影响到查询结果的顺序
The last parameter, as you would expect, affects the order by cause of our query,
它会把查询的结果按照日期降序排列
causing it to sort our result in descending order by date.
所有的query方法都会返回一个数据库Cursor（游标）对象
The query functions all return a database cursor.
Cursor对象是一种提供控制操作的数据结构  它可以遍历
A cursor object, is a control structure, that enables traversal over the rows and
查询结果集的行和列
columns of our query results set.
通常我们会通过调用cursor.moveToFirst来开始遍历
Typically, we'll start traversing results set by calling cursor.move
如果Cursor对象中没有查询的结果  则会返回false
to first, which will return false if there were no rows in the result,
也就是说没有数据符合查询的参数
which means nothing matched the query parameters.
我们可以通过moveToNext方法来遍历每一行
We can then call move to next, iterate through each row.
一旦Cursor对象指向了一行有效的数据  你就可以调用
Once the cursor points to a valid row, one can call get
getColumnIndex方法来返回数据库的属性在结果集中的索引值
column index to return the index of each database column within the results set.
你可以保存这些索引值  它们可以用于结果集中的每一行
You can save these values and use them for every row in the result.
然后你可以根据列的索引值
And then you can call get or methods,
调用获取这一行相应属性值的方法
that retrieve the values from that row based upon column index.
我们现在已经讨论了如何在我们的应用中
Everything we've covered so far, is how we read and
读写数据库
write from the database in our app.
测试和应用中的代码都有相关的内容
In tests and in our app code.
但是对于单元测试
For our unit test, though,
我们增加了一个验证的步骤  也就是使用断言来判断Cursor中的值
we add a step to validate the values from the cursor with the ones we
和最初创建ContentValues使用的值是否一样
originally created the contentValues object with, by using assert statements.
另外  当我们完成任务以后需要关闭Cursor和数据库
And, when we're finished we should close our cursor and
以尽快地释放系统资源
database to release the system resources as soon as possible